<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Members on Dalhousie Ocean Dynamics Group (DODG)</title><link>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/</link><description>Recent content in Members on Dalhousie Ocean Dynamics Group (DODG)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&amp;copy; DODG, 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 15:52:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clark Richards</title><link>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/clarkrichards/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/clarkrichards/</guid><description>I am a physical oceanographer who uses observations to study how ocean water is mixed and transformed. I am currently working as Research Scientist at the Bedford Institute of Oceanography in Halifax, Nova Scotia. Previously, I worked as a physical oceanographer with RBR in Ottawa, Ontario, and as a postdoctoral investigator at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution in Woods Hole Massachusetts.
I obtained my PhD in physical oceanography in 2012 from Dalhousie University, working with Dr.</description></item><item><title>Lina M. Rotermund</title><link>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/linarotermund/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/linarotermund/</guid><description>I joined the Dalhousie Ocean Dynamics Group (DODG) in September 2020, when I began my PhD under the supervision of Dr. Ruth Musgrave and Dr. Clark Richards.
My research examines the processes that modify water masses passing through the Canadian Arctic Archipelago, specifically within Barrow Strait, which is included in the Tallurutiup Imanga National Marine Conservation Area. Oceanic, sea ice, and atmospheric properties have been intermittently monitored since 1998 at five locations spanning the channel by the Department of Fisheries and Oceans Canada.</description></item><item><title>Marie Babineau</title><link>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/mariebabineau/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/mariebabineau/</guid><description>I am a graduate Student under the suppervision of Dr. Ruth Musgrave. My research focusses on the effects of depth varying current on lee wave propagation and energetics. I joined the group in 2020, after a bachelor’s degree in Water Engineering at Université Laval.
As for my hobbies, I play indoor and beach volleyball. I also enjoy trekking and rock climbing.</description></item><item><title>Ruby Yee</title><link>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/matdever/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/matdever/</guid><description>You can write $\LaTeX$ and Markdown here.
Minyae adgnoscitque fugiebat parentis ausum superos huius Ait erili meruisse iactatis omnibus erat Lorem markdownum natis, ipsi ipsi aut relictus saxo comitantibus aegro amori verba fugisse mira mortisque leones! Prior sui liquidissimus leve properandum totidem studio, refert magno, me quibus. Sternitur discordia summaque, si deus in undam et vulnere dirusque est felices pallam miserere curvamine comites. Tegumenque decipit suis, poscitur una dea sumus adnuerant, gerebat est edam plura.</description></item><item><title>Ruby Yee</title><link>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/rubyyee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/rubyyee/</guid><description>I am a MSc student currently working with Dr. Ruth Musgrave. My research focuses broadly on turbulence and mixing in the ocean and seeks to address questions like: what methods can be implemented to ensure that turbulence is quantified easily and accurately at sea? To what extent is mixing enhanced over topographical features like the Canada Basin shelf break in the Arctic Ocean? I am also working on a project closer to home&amp;mdash;a numerical model of mixing within Bedford Basin.</description></item><item><title>Ruth Musgrave</title><link>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/ruthmusgrave/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://daloceandynamicsgroup.github.io/member/ruthmusgrave/</guid><description>I study the the physics of the ocean, mostly at scales that are relevant to the forward cascade of energy towards 3D turbulence and ocean mixing. I am interested in both the processes that lead to ocean mixing, as well as the impact that mixing has on the physics, biology and chemistry of the ocean.</description></item></channel></rss>